<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kushashwa Ravi Shrimali (Kush)</title>
    <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kushashwa Ravi Shrimali (Kush)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://krshrimali.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What typing taught me in life?</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/03/what-typing-taught-me-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/03/what-typing-taught-me-in-life/</guid>
      <description>So this happened today, I was attempting a typing speed test on monkeytype and quickly realised a few things that kind of related in my personal life. Thought I&amp;rsquo;ll share with y&amp;rsquo;all and I&amp;rsquo;m confident you all will relate!&#xA;For context, I&amp;rsquo;ve been at around 120 wpm (avg) to 135 wpm (max) in a 30 seconds speed test for quite some time now (maybe more than a year at least). And very honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m happy about it, I don&amp;rsquo;t wwant to grow my typing speed further - in fact I never planned it before as well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a ChatBot from your Documentation Website | DocsGPT</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/02/building-a-chatbot-from-your-documentation-website-docsgpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/02/building-a-chatbot-from-your-documentation-website-docsgpt/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! Been a long time, thought I should talk about an ongoing project I&amp;rsquo;m working on.&#xA;Introduction - What are we trying to do here? Lemme start with some context and disclaimer first:&#xA;This was a part of an interview process in one of the amazing startups, and I wanted to extend it to an end-to-end project (kinda out of scope from the requirement of that interview process). I won&amp;rsquo;t be naming the startup here to help keep them anonymous and candid for their future candidates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Scrapping for ChatBot Model in Rust | DocsGPT | Part-2</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/02/data-scrapping-for-chatbot-model-in-rust-docsgpt-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/02/data-scrapping-for-chatbot-model-in-rust-docsgpt-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Alright everyone, we are back. Just FYI, we&amp;rsquo;ve had a blog on introduction to DocsGPT before: https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/02/building-a-chatbot-from-your-documentation-website-docsgpt/. This is a follow up blog where we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss data scraping and preprocessing to be able to finetune our model for ChatBot use-case.&#xA;Quick recap?&#xA;Input is going to be a single link to documentation page (index page). Need to fetch data for &amp;ldquo;all the internal pages&amp;rdquo;. Preprocess (and/or clean) and transform the data to be able to finetune the model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bring back the old times - celebrate your wins!</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/01/bring-back-the-old-times-celebrate-your-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/01/bring-back-the-old-times-celebrate-your-wins/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! Happy to be back, in case y&amp;rsquo;all have been wondering - where have you been Kush? Well, a lot of things have been happening on my YouTube channel and Twitch Channel - buffetcodes. But in any case, I wanted to write something out - so here it is.&#xA;Disclaimer: this is more on a personal level rather than on an educational level, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry to disappoint if you were expecting a detailed tech blog today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 3rd May 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-3rd-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-3rd-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>Okay, I think I should just accept this, while at work, it will be very hard for me to go and actually code something. And it makes sense, honestly at this stage - I feel like giving 50% of the time to reading + thinking, and 20% to implementing + 30% on iterating and feedback. So you&amp;rsquo;ll see more links about reading etc. over here.&#xA;Design a basic search engine (Google or Bing) | System Design Interview Prep Design a Payment System - System Design Interview That would be it, to be honest - not a lot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 2nd May 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-2nd-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-2nd-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>Today was more like a reading/learning day. Here are the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been watching:&#xA;Which Database Model to choose?: Why this? Going to be useful for the project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Thinking on directions of storing in-memory, using key-value model but let&amp;rsquo;s see. I made every sentry page 300 ms faster (intermediate) anthony explains #540 Why this? Always enjoy watching Anthony. Came on my YT recommendation, thought I&amp;rsquo;ll watch. Looks like a CDN config fix, also learnt a few things on watching the type of network calls (cached or not) from this video.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 1st May 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-1st-may-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/05/daily-update-1st-may-2023/</guid>
      <description>Interesting day, lots of design stuff for the project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on.&#xA;Designing flow for the word combinator service This is actually tricky, as we are figuring out how we&amp;rsquo;ll figure out the keystrokes into words/phrases (I&amp;rsquo;d like to call them entities at one point of time). The algorithm is close, and I&amp;rsquo;m particularly hopeful about it: It considers some edge cases of mouse events, sitting idle, and gives user the control what they would like to choose.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 30th April 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-30th-april-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-30th-april-2023/</guid>
      <description>Lovely day, had my friend imsrbh come over and we were talking about the project I wanted to do. He had some ideas and of course some experience with Kafka, so he helped me setup Kafka and docker on my machine, and that&amp;rsquo;s how it all started.&#xA;Setting up Kafka and Docker on my machine: Refer to this blog for Kafka setup. We verified by running a sample producer-consumer app in Python and it worked.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 29th April 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-29th-april-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-29th-april-2023/</guid>
      <description>Alright, we are back. It&amp;rsquo;s Saturday, so I spent a lot of time cleaning up my flat and my setup. Bengaluru is quite a dusty city, so yep, gotta clean regularly. Anyways, in terms of learning, my goals of today were to read some source code and papers/official documentation. It&amp;rsquo;s been some time since I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any Rust, so today I&amp;rsquo;ll just touch upon that as well.&#xA;Rust - building a UI to plot a sensor in real time Why this?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Update: 28th April 2023</title>
      <link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-28th-april-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2023/04/daily-update-28th-april-2023/</guid>
      <description>Started my day with talking to my family, and then kicking off work after getting ready. (Note: these blogs are mostly around my personal learning updates, so I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly miss anything that I do at work as that&amp;rsquo;s confidential)&#xA;What is OSI Model | Real World Examples Why this? The answer to: &amp;ldquo;How does the communication work from client to server&amp;rdquo; is very important in backend. I wanted to see if I missed anything from my graduate studies, but nothing much.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
