<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Personal on Kushashwa Ravi Shrimali (Kush)</title><link>https://krshrimali.github.io/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Kushashwa Ravi Shrimali (Kush)</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.8</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://krshrimali.github.io/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year older!</title><link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2025/06/one-year-older/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2025/06/one-year-older/</guid><description>&lt;p>I generally don&amp;rsquo;t do this, but I thought this would be a good time to reflect on the past year and share some thoughts with you all. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year since I turned 30, and I wanted to take a moment to appreciate the journey so far.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Haha, gotta turn off copilot for this one. I&amp;rsquo;m not 30. I guess, LLMs can&amp;rsquo;t express how I feel and how old I am right now. Very obvious!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What typing taught me in life?</title><link>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/03/what-typing-taught-me-in-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://krshrimali.github.io/posts/2024/03/what-typing-taught-me-in-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>So this happened today, I was attempting a typing speed test on &lt;a href="https://monkeytype.com">monkeytype&lt;/a> and quickly realised a few things that kind of related in my personal life. Thought I&amp;rsquo;ll share with y&amp;rsquo;all and I&amp;rsquo;m confident you all will relate!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For context, I&amp;rsquo;ve been at around 120 wpm (avg) to 135 wpm (max) in a 30 seconds speed test for quite some time now (maybe more than a year at least). And very honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m happy about it, I don&amp;rsquo;t wwant to grow my typing speed further - in fact I never planned it before as well. I used to just type as fast as my fingers would allow, and turns out it was good enough for me to do my work. Right now, my goal is more towards sustaining my wrists and fingers along with work, as it definitely pains a lot if your positioning is not right.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>